hey everybody welcome back to three
questions this is Chris and today I have
Melody Perkins with me who I've known
like 25 years or something ridiculous
like that I think that's right and she
is married to Todd for how long have you
guys been
married 16 years so she had to think
about it for a minute yeah I'm so glad
she's here I remember um I think the
first semester I was in seminary I
called Melanie I think I called you said
hey I want can I come have lunch with
you and hear about what you do and she's
still doing it which is amazing so first
I'm going to ask you our three questions
there's so much she could tell us but
I'm just going to ask her three first
tell us what's your little corner of the
kingdom and what do you do
there okay hi Chris I'm at in St Louis
at Grace and peace Fellowship it's a
smallish PCA church on the edge of the
city we've been here as a church for
about 55 years and I've been here
28 years and 25 years
full-time working for the shelter as the
ministry team leader and the ministry
facilitator for the rest of my hours I
lead all the aspects of our ministry
that has been Sheltering homeless women
through our cold winter nights in St
Louis since
1986 so I've been here 25 Winters doing
that our Ministry not only gives the
women love shelter and basic necessities
but as we were talking about before it
also trains Believers and anyone with
the interest and a Compassionate Heart
who may or may not be a believer to work
with the poor instead of being
intimidated by them or confused about
what to do and one Central Foundation
really the Central Foundation of our
ministry is that we want to reflect to
people by what we do and what we say
that they are people each one of them
created in God's image and treasured by
that Creator who made them so that is
what we are all about this big and busy
world that we all live in doesn't say or
reflect that very many times at all to
anyone so that is what we are all about
in our shelter
work and that's the story 25 years 25
about 25 years it'll be 25 years later
this year yep that's amazing and we
before we were recording I was saying
you can see this P there's a picture
behind Melody you don't have to point to
it but you can see it in the screen that
when she comes back on that um that was
a woman who was a guest in the shelter
and they're called guests right and um
that's right they're treated like guests
and we my daughter and I have worked
there several times and it's one like
it's wonderful to go it's it's a
wonderful place to be can you tell us do
you have a specific story you can tell
us about God working through the shelter
Ministry recently sure and Chris it's
been a great joy to have you and your
daughter involved for a long time ever
since she was a little girl too little
little um so there are so many stories
but here's one that keeps coming to mind
there was a young woman who I'll call
Mary who phoned me just six nights
before we were scheduled to close for
this winter so that was almost mid-march
when she called she had just turned 18
and she was being kicked out of her
mother and stepfather's home because she
hadn't gotten a job during the first six
days that she'd been an
adult so she was very sad and
Afraid and she was failing 12th grade
because her school bus kept failing to
pick her up and her parents would not
take her to school so she had missed so
many days that she was sure she was
going to not
graduate and I said you know we have one
bed open why don't you come on Oak so
she came over she was the
sweetest most mannerly young lady that
you have ever seen and she was just as
Tiny as a minute
and she came and stayed five nights and
during that time we were able to not
only give her shelter and feed her
when she needed it she was little as a
minute so she really wasn't eating a lot
but she did go to school a couple of
those days and she um got in touch with
an aunt of hers who lived in another
state and that Aunt drove all the way up
here from Louisiana and picked her up
and took her back to Louisiana to live
in a safe home where she can go to
school finish High School got her ID and
her birth certificate back and she can
begin her young adulthood in a safe
place and a safe way and so that is one
of the stories that we were able to do
with God's help this spring this yeah
and if you if you asked Melody those who
are listening she would tell you lots of
stories like this like she has lots of
stories about different people in
different places and different of those
25 years and it's just so encouraging to
hear so how can we your brothers and
sisters in your denomination if you
could think of a way that we could help
encourage and support you in this work
that you do what would it be I would say
three things the first thing I would say
is pray and that would be pray for me
pray for our guests pray for anybody you
know that is spending their time dayt
day and night tonight working with the
people that are in these hard situations
and walking with
them just imagine yourself for a moment
if you were doing that what would you
want to be prayed for pray that for
us also I would say if you have a
chance start a Ministry doesn't have to
be a shelter maybe it's a weekend
shelter maybe it's an Outreach where you
go out and talk to people that are
sitting on the streets homeless and you
buy them lunch and maybe you share the
gospel with them or maybe you just buy
them
lunch and or get involved yourself or
your church with another Ministry church
that has the equipping or the calling to
do that type of a Ministry and just get
involved because you will be an
essential part of that Ministry if
you're offering yourself to serve you
yourself will be blessing that Ministry
but you also will be growing and your
people in your congregation will be
growing as you join and the third thing
that I would say is certainly if you get
half a chance donate God is very very
generous to those of us who are working
in his work for the poor but certainly
donate if you have a
chance those are the things the three
things I would say up front so I love
your challenge to us to go at least get
involved or start one yourself it is
kind of crazy to think like Grace and
peace is not huge but God has just over
the years given money and people and
meals and it just keeps going which is
so encouraging thank you for telling us
your brothers and sisters what God's
doing in this little little corner of St
Louis thank you are welcome and it's my
great pleasure thanks